https://www.essendant.com/privacy-notice

Skip to content
Linkedin page opens in new windowFacebook page opens in new windowContact us Microwidget Menu 1
Search:
Search
ABOUT USLOCATIONS ESSENDANT LEADERSHIP OUR VALUESGIVING BACK DIVERSITY AND INCLUSION SUSTAINABILITY ASSOCIATE SAFETY
OUR HISTORY
CUSTOMERSMARKETING AND DIGITAL SERVICESDIGITAL MARKETING ANALYSIS AND OPTIMIZATION
RESELLER TOOLSBUSINESS SUPPORT TOOLS SALES SUPPORT OPERATIONS SUPPORT
FOR EXISTING CUSTOMERS PRODUCT CATEGORIES
SUPPLIERSSUPPLIER RESOURCES PRODUCT SUPPLIER SERVICE PROVIDER
CAREERS POWERING MORE
Essendant Privacy Notice (“Privacy Notice” or “Notice”)
This Privacy Notice describes our handling of Personal Information in connection with your use of our websites, mobile apps and the services we provide. By using our websites and services, you hereby consent to these terms.
“Personal Information” refers to information that identifies you as an individual. This Privacy Notice describes how we will collect, use, share, and protect your Personal Information, and choices you have regarding your Personal Information. We encourage you to read this Privacy Notice.
Capitalized terms not otherwise defined in this Notice have the meanings given to them in the Definitions section.
Effective Date
June 1, 2015 (Updated as of January 1, 2020)
Your Consent
By using any website owned by Essendant Co., an Illinois corporation (or one of its affiliates) on which the Notice is posted, you are consenting to the collection, use, and disclosure of information, including your Personal Information, as set forth in this Notice.  If you do not agree to be bound by this Notice, you may not access or use our Sites.
This Notice is Part of Our Terms of Use
This Notice is part of the Terms of Use that govern your use of our Sites.  We typically provide a link to our Terms of Use in the universal footer of our Sites.
Other Agreements
When you sign up to use a special feature of our Sites, you may be asked to agree to special terms governing your use of the special feature.  In such cases, you may be asked to expressly consent to the special terms, for example, by checking a box or clicking on a button marked “I agree.”  This type of agreement is known as a “click-through” agreement.  If any of the terms of the click-through agreement are different than the terms of this Notice, the terms of the click-through agreement will supplement or amend this Notice, but only with respect to the matters governed by the click-through agreement.
Types of Information We Collect
Information You Manually Provide.  Essendant collects the information—including Personal Information—you knowingly and manually provide when you use our Sites or otherwise transact business with us.  For example:
If you apply to become a reseller, we will ask you to provide your name, company name, email address, and other information.
If you order products through one of our Sites, we will ask you to provide the information we need to process and ship your order.
If you use a “contact us” form to ask us a question, we will collect whatever Personal Information you submit with or include in your question.
If you submit a product review, we will collect whatever Personal Information you submit with your review.
The type of Personal Information we collect varies depending upon how you use our Sites.
Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser.  We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your web browser.  This information typically includes your IP address, the identity of your Internet service provider, the name and version of your operating system, the name and version of your browser, the date and time of your visit, and the pages on our Sites that you visit.  Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings.
Your IP address is the identifier assigned to your particular computer when you access the Internet.  IP addresses do not include your name, email address or other Personal Information, but in some cases, they can be used to identify you.  For example, if you have registered with our Sites, we may link your IP address to account information that identifies you personally.  We may also use IP addresses in connection with other information gathered elsewhere in an attempt to learn the identities or general geographic locations of people who visit our Sites.  If we suspect inappropriate or criminal activity or a threat to our Sites or their users, we may share our server logs—which contain users’ IP addresses—with the appropriate investigative authorities, who could use that information to trace and identify individuals.
Cookies and Similar Technologies.  Most websites use cookies and/or similar technologies to place information about a user’s visit to that website in a small data text file that is stored on the user’s computer.  In general, we use cookies and other web technologies to:
collect information about the ways visitors use our Sites—which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page;
support the features and functionality of our Sites—for example, to save you the trouble of reentering information already in our database or to prompt the settings you established on previous visits; and
personalize your experience when you use our Sites, including serving you targeted content/advertisements.
Generally, the information we collect using these web technologies does not identify you personally.  If, however, you have created a user account, we may link the information we collect using these web technologies to other information that identifies you personally.
If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may be able to set the browser of your computer to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is delivered.  You may also be able to delete our cookies as soon as you leave our Sites.  Although you are not required to accept our cookies when you visit our Sites, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features and functionality of our Sites.
Information from your mobile device.  If you access one of our websites through your mobile device, we may automatically collect certain information from or about your mobile device.  The types of information we may collect include the type of device you use, your device’s unique ID, the IP address of your device, your device’s operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use our mobile website.
Using GPS technology, we may also collect precise, real-time location information from your mobile device and use that information to deliver tailored content through our mobile websites.  Your mobile device may allow you to adjust your settings so that location information is not available to any mobile website or application.  If you have questions about the security and privacy settings of your mobile device, please refer to instructions from your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your device.
Information Collected by Third–Party Cookies
In addition to the cookies Essendant delivers to your computer through our Sites, certain third parties may deliver cookies to you for a variety of reasons.  For example, we may use Google Analytics, a web analytics tool that helps us understand how visitors engage with our Sites. You can opt-out of tracking used to understand website utilization provided by Google Analytics by visiting https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
How We Use Information Collected Through Our Sites
Generally, we use the information we collect through our Sites:
to provide the information, products and services you request;
to provide you with effective customer service;
to provide you with a personalized experience when you use our Sites;
to contact you with information and notices related to your use of our Sites;
to contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
to invite you to participate in surveys and provide Feedback to us (in accordance with any privacy preferences you have expressed to us);
to improve the content, functionality and usability of our Sites;
to better understand your needs and interests;
to improve our products and services;
to improve our marketing and promotional efforts;
for security, credit or fraud prevention purposes; and
for any other purpose identified in an applicable privacy notice, click-through agreement or other agreement between you and us.
Please see below for information about the choices you have about the ways we use your Personal Information.
Use of Aggregated Information
We may use information gathered through our Sites to create a compiled, aggregate view of our Sites’ visitors and their usage patterns. We use aggregated information to operate our services and to better understand visitors to our Sites as we develop new products and services.  We may also share aggregated information with our third-party service providers as well as with other third parties so they can better understand the market we serve.  Aggregate information is not personally identifiable.
Use of Survey Information
From time to time, we may post a survey on our Sites or, if we have your contact information, we may send you a questionnaire or survey.  We compile statistical information from the responses to our surveys.  These statistics are not personally identifiable.  These statistics help us understand your needs and preferences and improve the content and functionality of our Sites.
How to Access, Update or Correct Your Personal Information
If you have registered on our Sites, you may be able to access, update or correct the Personal Information you have submitted to us through your account.  If you are unclear as to how to access, update or correct your Personal Information, please contact us using the Contact Us link below.  We will respond to you within a reasonable time and, in any case, within the time limits established by applicable law.  We may ask you for additional information to verify your identity.  In most cases, we will provide access and correct or delete any inaccurate information you discover.  In some cases, however, we may limit or deny your request if the law permits or requires us to do so or if we are unable to verify your identity. Note also that Essendant customers may contact Customer Care at  (800) 733-4000 regarding their account information.
How We Protect Your Personal Information
We employ technical, physical and administrative safeguards to protect your Personal Information.   However, we cannot guarantee your information will be completely safe against unauthorized access. Please use caution when sharing your information with others and take appropriate measures to protect the confidentiality of your username and password for our Sites.
If you think the Personal Information you provided to us has been improperly accessed or used, please contact us immediately. See the section of this Privacy Notice titled “Contact Us” for guidance on how to do so.
Our websites may contain links to, or plugins or widgets from, social media or other websites operated and maintained by Third Parties. These properties, which we do not control, operate independently and have their own privacy practices and statements, which we encourage you to review.  Further, we cannot control dissemination of Personal Information contained in User-Generated Content you post on or through our Sites, and you should have no expectation of privacy in such information.
How We Share Your Personal Information with Others
With Credit Card Payment Processors.  Some of our Sites permit you to use a credit card to order and pay for products online.  We work with a third-party vendor to process your credit card payment, and we never receive, process, or store your credit card number.  We provide to the vendor not only the minimal data it needs to process your payment but also enhanced product information (such as the names of the products you purchased and their unit price).  The vendor and other downstream payment processors use this data to process your transaction and to provide to you a more detailed credit card statement.
With Other Third-Party Service Providers.  Essendant shares information—including Personal Information—collected through our Sites with other third-party service providers, as well.  For example, we may use third-party vendors to design, operate, and/or host our Sites; to conduct surveys; to fulfill orders; and to help us with our promotional efforts. These third parties may need information about you to perform their functions.  They are permitted to use your Personal Information only to perform services on our behalf.
With Our Suppliers.  From time to time, we may share your Personal Information with our suppliers.  For example, to obtain a rebate on a product you purchased from us, we may need to share your Personal Information or that of the product’s end-user with the supplier that provides the rebate.
In the Course of Business Negotiations.  We may contemplate, for strategic or other reasons, selling, buying, merging, or otherwise reorganizing one or more of our businesses.  In negotiating with a third party about entering into such an arrangement, we may need to disclose your Personal Information.  In such cases, we will take reasonable measures to protect the Personal Information we disclose, for example, by requiring a prospective purchaser to sign a nondisclosure agreement limiting the use and protecting the confidentiality of the Personal Information.
As a Result of a Business Transfer.  We may transfer the Personal Information you submit on or through our Sites to any organization that acquires or merges with us.
To Comply with Laws and Protection of Our Rights and the Rights of Others.  We may disclose your Personal Information when we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law, a court order or a subpoena.  We may also disclose your Personal Information to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to protect the security of our Sites; to enforce or apply our online Terms of Use or other agreements; or to protect our own rights or property or the rights, property or safety of our users or others.
As Described in a Click-Through Agreement.  We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information as described in any click-through agreement to which you have agreed.
User-Generated Content.  The User-Generated Content you submit on or through our Sites is available to others who visit our Sites.  Any Personal Information contained in User-Generated Content you submit can be read, viewed, collected, or used by others, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  In addition, we may use User-Generated Content you submit on or through our Sites in connection with advertising campaigns and other promotions.  We may or may not use your name in connection with such use, and we may or may not seek further consent before using the content for such purposes.  Therefore, you should have no expectation of privacy with respect to User-Generated Content you submit on or through our Sites.  You should not submit any User-Generated Content you do not wish to make available to the general public, and you must take special care to make sure your submissions comply with our Terms of Use.  In particular, your submissions must not violate the privacy or other rights of others.
Minors
Our websites and mobile applications are intended for a general audience and are not directed toward minors under 16 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect their Personal Information.
Links to Other Sites
Our Sites may provide links to other websites operated by third parties.  We expect our partners and providers of products and services to be transparent about their data protection practices.  Be aware, however, that we have no control over third-party websites.  This Notice does not apply to Personal Information collected on any third-party website.  When you access third-party websites through a link on our Sites, please take a few minutes to review the privacy notice posted on that site.
Information for Visitors Accessing Our Sites from Outside the United States
Essendant Co. is a U.S. corporation headquartered in the United States. Our Sites are currently hosted on servers located in the United States, although we reserve the right to relocate our Sites to other servers elsewhere in the world.  Your Personal Information may be stored on servers located within the United States or in another country.  In addition, we may transfer your Personal Information to our service providers and others located in the United States or another country for the purposes described in this Notice.  Different countries have different privacy laws and requirements, and some provide less legal protection for your Personal Information than others.
BY USING OUR SITES OR OTHERWISE PROVIDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE COLLECTION, USE, AND TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN OR TO THE UNITED STATES OR TO ANY OTHER COUNTRY IN THE WORLD SUBJECT TO THE TERMS OF THIS NOTICE.
This Notice May Change
This Notice describes Essendant’s current policies and practices with regard to the information, including Personal Information, we collect.
We are continually improving and adding to the features and functionality of our Sites and the services we offer through our Sites.  As a result of these changes (or changes in the law), we may need to update or revise this Notice.  Accordingly, we reserve the right to update or modify this Notice at any time, without prior notice, by posting the revised version of this Notice behind the link marked “Privacy Notice” in the universal footer of the Sites governed by this Notice.  Your continued use of our Sites after we have posted the revised Notice constitutes your agreement to be bound by the revised Notice.  If you have not used our Sites recently, be sure you check the effective date to see if this Notice has been revised since your last visit.
You may access the current version of this Notice at any time by clicking the link marked “Privacy Notice” in the universal footer of the Sites governed by this Notice.
Definitions
The term “Content” refers to all of the software and code comprising or used to operate our Sites, and all of the text, photographs, images, illustrations, graphics, sound recordings, video and audio-video clips, and other materials available on our Sites, including User-Generated Content.
The term “Feedback” refers to the Content you post on or through our Sites that is specifically about how we can improve our Sites and the products and services we make available through our Sites.
The term “Notice” refers to this privacy notice.
The term our “Sites” refers collectively to Essendant-owned websites on which this Notice is posted.
The terms “Essendant,” “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to the owner of this Site, which may be Essendant Co. or one of its subsidiaries.
The term “User-Generated Content” refers to all of the text, photographs, images, illustrations, graphics, sound recordings, video, audio-video clips, and other Content that you post on or through our Sites using the social networking tools we make available to you and that does not constitute Feedback.  One way that User-Generated Content differs from other information you provide to us is that, once submitted, User-Generated Content is made available instantaneously to others.  Examples of User-Generated Content include product reviews and comments posted to discussion boards.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this Notice or our privacy practices, please contact us using the information provided below:
privacy@essendant.com.
NEVADA RESIDENTS:
Under Nevada SB 220, Nevada residents may submit an opt-out request regarding the sale of their Personally Identifiable Information (PII) collected through a website or online service.  Essendant does not sell any PII as defined by Nevada SB200.
CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS:
California Shine the Light Law
Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83–1798.84 California residents may request the names and addresses of affiliated companies and categories of Personal Information we share for their direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please email us at privacy@essendant.com.
California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018
California residents have the following rights:
The Right to Disclosure
About information collected
About information sold
Categories of personal information sold
Categories of Third Parties with whom the personal information was sold
The Right to Deletion of Personal Information
The Right to Opt-Out of the sale of Personal Information to Third Parties
The Right to Sue for Security Breaches
The Right to not be Discriminated Against Based on Exercising any of the Above Rights
Where applicable, you may submit your request to Opt-Out of the sale of your Personal Information to Third Parties by submitting an online request here: Do Not Sell My Personal Information
We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity prior to fulfilling the above requests.
Authorized Agents may submit requests on behalf of a California resident using the above processes and providing the appropriate documentation.
The following section describes:
Categories of personal information we collect
The purpose for which the personal information is collected
Specific personal information collected
Categories of sources from which that information is collected
Categories of Third Parties (who are not classified as service providers) with whom the information may be shared
The purpose for selling or sharing of personal information
Categories of Personal Information as defined by CCPA
Do we collect this type of Personal Information?
Purpose of collecting the Personal Information
Specific Personal Information that may be Collected
Categories of Sources from which the Personal Information is Collected
Is this category of Personal Information shared with Third Parties?
Categories of Third Parties with which the Personal Information may be Shared
Purpose of Selling or Sharing Personal Information
Can you opt-out of this Sharing?
Identifiers
Yes
To uniquely identify an individual in support of business activities
Names, Account ids, emails, addresses, IP Addresses, Device Identifiers,Tax Exempt Numbers
From you
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
Commercial Information
Yes
To support business transaction
Quotes, Sales Transactions,
Your transactions with us
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
Biometrics
No
N/A
Yes
(if you access our websites or mobile apps)
To allow access to and optimize our websites
Access to our properties
From you
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
Geolocation Data
Yes
(if you access our websites or mobile apps)
Personalization
Unique Identifiers and your location and ZIP code
From you and your devices
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
Recordings (e.g. audio, visual)
Yes (if you call customer service or visit a distribution center using security cameras)
Customer Service, Fraud Prevention
Voice and CCTV Recordings
From you
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
Professional or Employment-Related Information
N/A
Notice to Job Applicants/Job Applicants Privacy Statement:
Your privacy is important to Essendant Co. and its subsidiaries (“Essendant”). Our Job Applicant Privacy Statement explains Essendant’s commitment to protecting your privacy. Please review this statement before submitting an online job application.
Notice for applicants within the United States: Federal law requires all employers to verify the identity and employment eligibility of all persons hired to work in the United States. Essendant participates in E-Verify. We will provide the Social Security Administration (SSA) and, if necessary, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), with information from each new employee’s Form I-9 to confirm work authorization. Important: If the Government cannot confirm that you are authorized to work, this employer is required to provide you written instructions and an opportunity to contact SSA and/or DHS before taking adverse action against you, including terminating your employment. For more information on E-Verify, please contact DHS at 1-888-464-4218.
Submitting information to Essendant. Your application and information, which includes “personal data” submitted while using a website, will be held in confidence and only be used by Essendant for job application/recruitment purposes, human resources analysis, and employment purposes.  Unless legally required to do otherwise, Essendant will share your data only with those vendors hired to provide employment verification services for Essendant or Essendant human resource services providers, but always under conditions of confidentiality.  Essendant will not trade or sell your personal information for use by any other company without your prior consent.  The term “Essendant” in this Privacy Statement includes Essendant Co. (One Parkway North Boulevard, Deerfield, IL, 60015, USA) and its subsidiaries.
The information you submit will be accessible only by the Essendant personnel involved in the job application and recruitment processes.  BY TRANSMITTING INFORMATION TO ESSENDANT VIA A WEBSITE, YOU EXPLICITLY CONSENT, UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT ESSENDANT MAY USE THAT INFORMATION FOR JOB APPLICATION/RECRUITMENT, HUMAN RESOURCES ANALYSIS, AND EMPLOYMENT PURPOSES.  THIS INCLUDES:
Circulating the information to various Essendant managers and supervisors;
Using this information to evaluate you as a candidate for a position with Essendant;
Disclosing the information to Essendant managers or supervisors who may have a position for which you appear to be qualified.
The transmission and storage of your information to a secure data center in the US, managed by an application service provider chosen by Essendant. This transmission to the US is secured through the application service providers safe harbor certification;
If a job offer is extended, your information may also be shared with a Essendant vendor assisting in the hiring process.
Using the information to comply with applicant and workforce reporting requirements as mandated by law
Personal data. Your personal data will be processed during the recruitment process by the Essendant local affiliate to which you apply for a job position, its affiliates and contracted parties for job application/recruitment purposes, human resources analysis and employment purposes. You have the right of access to your data and the right to rectify and cancel these data, as well as the right to object to the processing of your data. Responses to questions requesting personal data are voluntary if there are no legal requirements. By using a website to apply for a job with Essendant, you agree that you will not supply personal sensitive data to support your application or as part of your personal profile in our applicant tracking system if it is not clearly demanded to do so.  Personal sensitive data could include: racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, religious, party or trade-union membership, as well as data concerning health, genetic code, addictions or sex life and data relating to convictions, decisions on penalty, fines and other decisions issued in court or administrative proceedings.
Information Collected by Placing a “Cookie” On Your Computer. The job application website utilized by Essendant may use “session cookies.”  A session cookie is used to tag your computer with a computer-generated, unique identifier when you access the site.  A session cookie does not identify you personally and expires after you close your browser. Session cookies may be used to collect statistical information about the ways visitors use a site.
Access to Personal Information. At any time, you may review, correct and update the personal information that you provide to us on the job search site by logging in with your user name and password and then by clicking the “My Presence” link and navigating to “Personal Information.”
Go to Top
